{"test_questions": [[{"question": "What happens when we try to compile the class definition in following code snippet?\nclass Birds {};\nclass Peacock : protected Birds {};", "opta": "It will not compile because class body of Birds is not defined.", "optb": "It will not compile because class body of Peacock is not defined.", "optc": "It will not compile because a class cannot be protectedly inherited from other class.", "optd": "It will compile succesfully.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is incorrect?", "opta": "Friend keyword can be used in the class to allow access to another class.", "optb": "Friend keyword can be used for a function in the public section of a class.", "optc": "Friend keyword can be used for a function in the private section of a class.", "optd": "Friend keyword can be used on main().", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct regarding destructor of base class?", "opta": "Destructor of base class should always be static.", "optb": "Destructor of base class should always be virtual.", "optc": "Destructor of base class should not be virtual.", "optd": "Destructor of base class should always be private.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following two entities (reading from Left to Right) can be connected by the dot operator?", "opta": "A class member and a class object.", "optb": "A class object and a class.", "optc": "A class and a member of that class.", "optd": "A class object and a member of that class.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How can we make a class abstract?", "opta": "By making all member functions constant.", "optb": "By making at least one member function as pure virtual function.", "optc": "By declaring it abstract using the static keyword.", "optd": "By declaring it abstract using the virtual keyword.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is correct when a class is inherited publicly?", "opta": "Public members of the base class become protected members of derived class.", "optb": "Public members of the base class become private members of derived class.", "optc": "Private members of the base class become protected members of derived class.", "optd": "Public members of the base class become public members of derived class.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the constructors and destructors?", "opta": "Destructors can take arguments but constructors cannot.", "optb": "Constructors can take arguments but destructors cannot.", "optc": "Destructors can be overloaded but constructors cannot be overloaded.", "optd": "Constructors and destructors can both return a value.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following access specifies is used in a class definition by default?", "opta": "Protected", "optb": "Public", "optc": "Private", "optd": "Friend", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct with respect to the use of friend keyword inside a class?", "opta": "A private data member can be declared as a friend.", "optb": "A class may be declared as a friend.", "optc": "An object may be declared as a friend.", "optd": "We can use friend keyword as a class name.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following keywords is used to control access to a class member?", "opta": "Default", "optb": "Break", "optc": "Protected", "optd": "Asm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following can access private data members or member functions of a class?", "opta": "Any function in the program.", "optb": "All global functions in the program.", "optc": "Any member function of that class.", "optd": "Only public member functions of that class.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following type of data member can be shared by all instances of its class?", "opta": "Public", "optb": "Inherited", "optc": "Static", "optd": "Friend", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following also known as an instance of a class?", "opta": "Friend Functions", "optb": "Object", "optc": "Member Functions", "optd": "Member Variables", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Constructor is executed when _____.", "opta": "an object is created", "optb": "an object is used", "optc": "a class is declared", "optd": "an object goes out of scope.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements about virtual base classes is correct?", "opta": "It is used to provide multiple inheritance.", "optb": "It is used to avoid multiple copies of base class in derived class.", "optc": "It is used to allow multiple copies of base class in a derived class.", "optd": "It allows private members of the base class to be inherited in the derived class.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many objects can be created from an abstract class?", "opta": "Zero", "optb": "One", "optc": "Two", "optd": "As many as we want", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does the class definitions in following code represent?\nclass Bike\n{\n    Engine objEng;\n};\nclass Engine\n{\n    float CC;\n};", "opta": "kind of relationship", "optb": "has a relationship", "optc": "Inheritance", "optd": "Both A and B", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is correct when a class is inherited privately?", "opta": "Public members of the base class become protected members of derived class.", "optb": "Public members of the base class become private members of derived class.", "optc": "Private members of the base class become private members of derived class.", "optd": "Public members of the base class become public members of derived class.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is correct?", "opta": "Data items in a class must be private.", "optb": "Both data and functions can be either private or public.", "optc": "Member functions of a class must be private.", "optd": "Constructor of a class cannot be private.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does a class hierarchy depict?", "opta": "It shows the relationships between the classes in the form of an organization chart.", "optb": "It describes \"has a\" relationships.", "optc": "It describes \"kind of\" relationships.", "optd": "It shows the same relationship as a family tree.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following can be overloaded?", "opta": "Object", "optb": "Functions", "optc": "Operators", "optd": "Both B and C", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following means \"The use of an object of one class in definition of another class\"?", "opta": "Encapsulation", "optb": "Inheritance", "optc": "Composition", "optd": "Abstraction", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the only technical difference between structures and classes in C++?", "opta": "Member function and data are by default protected in structures but private in classes.", "optb": "Member function and data are by default private in structures but public in classes.", "optc": "Member function and data are by default public in structures but private in classes.", "optd": "Member function and data are by default public in structures but protected in classes.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the program given below?\nclass Bix\n{\n    public:\n    static void MyFunction();\n};\nint main()\n{\n    void(*ptr)() = &Bix::MyFunction;\n    return 0; \n}", "opta": "The program reports an error as pointer to member function cannot be defined outside the definition of class.", "optb": "The program reports an error as pointer to static member function cannot be defined.", "optc": "The program reports an error as pointer to member function cannot be defined without object.", "optd": "The program reports linker error.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements are correct for a static member function?\n  It can access only other static members of its class.\n  It can be called using the class name, instead of objects.", "opta": "Only 1 is correct.", "optb": "Only 2 is correct.", "optc": "Both 1 and 2 are correct.", "optd": "Both 1 and 2 are incorrect.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}